Carolina I. Yoedhana

Seattle, WA 98101 | carolinayo | linkedin.com/in/yoedhanac

Summary

Multi-disciplinary Front-End Web Developer with professional certification in Full Stack Web Development. Experienced in developing a web application using JavaScript, CSS, MySql, and MERN stack. A responsible, self-motivated team player.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML/CSS, Javascript, JQuery

Libraries / Tools: Bootstrap, Node, Express, React, MySQL, and MongoDB.

Other: Heroku, Git, MYOB accounting system-MYOB South Asia.

Technical Projects

GROUP PROJECT: THE GIF'D OF FOOD | https://carolinayo.github.io/the-gifd-of-food/| https://github.com/CarolinaYo/the-gifd-of-food.git This is a recipe search application that allows users to select and display details of the selected recipe with fun Gifs that matched its recipe keyword alongside for a lighthearted laugh. Users can save, and retrieve selected recipes.

- Collaborated with a team of 4 focusing on back-end coding and testing.
- Created project wireframe with Balsamiq
- Completed projects remotely using Zoom and Slack.
- Managed work progress through GitHub Kanban board.
- Technologies used: HTML5, UI kit CSS framework, JQuery, and local storage.

The Weather Dashboard | https://github.com/CarolinaYo/weather-dashboard-cy.git The Weather Dashboard allows users to retrieve current and 5-day forecast weather data from a selected city.

- Individual project: Developed the web application from conception to deployment.
- Retrieved data from a third-party API: OpenWeather API.
- Utilized local storage approach to persist data.
- Technologies used: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript with JQuery Library.

GOOGLE BOOK SEARCH https://book-search-mern.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/CarolinaYo/google-book-search.git
This application allows users to perform a book search, persist selected book, view, and delete the selection.

- Individual project: Developed the web application from conception to deployment
- Retrieves data from Google Books API.
- Deployed live application through HEROKU server with MongoDB Atlas cloud database service.
- Developed using MongoDB, Express, React, and Node (MERN) stack.

Work Experience

Preschool Lead Teacher | Newport Children School | Bellevue, WA

September 2019 – July 2020

Effectively managed a classroom of 12 children in a limited shared space and consistently met with licensing student ratio requirement that allows the center to fully maximize its capacity.

• Promoted to Lead Teacher position within one month of hire as a float with proven knowledge and skills.

Pre-K teacher | Kids Connection Preschool | Foster City, CA

November 2017 - June 2019

Lead children age group 2 to 5 years old in addition to being a primary Pre-K teacher with the responsibility of formulating monthly lesson plans, performing assessments, and maintaining continuous communications with parents/caregivers.

• Number 1 on the list of substitute teachers - consistently demonstrating adaptability, & flexibility in the classroom.

Provided support to all Finance staff handling documents for signatory; logging routed items; processing reimbursements and vacation requests; updating Capital Finance team calendar.

• Direct support to the Capital Finance Director's responsible for maintaining meeting arrangements, agendas, and correspondence.

Part-Time Administrative Assistant | Precision Plastics, LLC. | Union City, CA April 2016 – February 2017 Processes of Sales, Purchase Orders, Accounts Receivable, and Accounts Payable using QuickBooks™ Premier with minimal training.

• Handled one-week transition and worked with minimal supervision as owner's representative handling customer inquiries.

Manager for Administrative Department | U.D. Trimurti | Denpasar, Bali September 2013 - May 2015 Lead the department to fully implement and operate new MYOB™ East Asia accounting system that handles Point of Sales, Inventory, Purchase Orders, Invoices, and Financial record.

• Able to reduce redundant record-keeping that allows the department to produce tax reports that meet the required monthly deadline.

Preschool Lead Teacher | Hearts and Hands Preschool | Fremont, CA

April 2012 - May 2013

Demonstrated self-motivation and teamwork as the primary teacher to 12 three-year-old full day group that helps the classroom's enrollment to full capacity as the new center faced challenges in hiring assistance.

• Recognized by the congregation as excelling new teacher of the year.

Education

Coding Boot Camp | Febuary 2021 | University of Washington, Seattle, WA

• Full Stack Web Development Certification

Certificate of Achievement | December 2011 | Ohlone College, Fremont, CA

• Early Childhood Education

Master of Business Administration | 13 December 2001 | University of San Francisco, CA

• Major: E-Commerce

Bachelor of Science | 4 September 1998 | California State University - East Bay, CA

- Major: Business Administration
 - Option: Computer Information Systems and Business Computer Telecommunications